Guide to the Frederick Joerg Papers, 1942-1967
Duke University. University Archives
Frederick Joerg papers circa 1942-1967
Duke University. University Archives
Joerg, Frederick.
3.0 linear feet Extent: 2000 Items
Frederick Joerg joined Duke University in 1948 as an assistant professor of Economics. He later became a professor of Business Administration and Forest Management, and he worked in university administration as the Assistant Dean of the College of Arts and Sciences and Assistant Provost for Academic Administration starting in the 1960s. Joerg retired in 1983. Material includes lecture notes, papers concerning the Southeastern Personnel Conference, and papers related to Joerg's administrative duties at Duke.
UA.29.02.0149
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Frederick Joerg Papers were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1979.
Biographical Note
Frederick Joerg joined Duke University in 1948 as an assistant professor of Economics; he retired in 1983. During his time at Duke Joerg taught as a professor of economics, business administration and forest management. Additionally he served as assistant dean of the College of Arts and Sciences, and as assistant provost for Academic Administration. Joerg passed away in 1983.
Chronology List
1939 Received Bachelor's Degree from Fordham University
1940-1946 Worked and Taught at the Army Finance School
1947 Received Masters in Business Administration from Harvard University
1948 Becomes Assistant Professor of Economics at Duke University
1959 Awarded a Fulbright Grant to Lecture and Study in Finland for the 1959-1960 Academic Year
1965 Becomes Assistant Dean of the College of Arts and Sciences
1969 Becomes Assistant Provost for Academic Affairs
1983 Retires from Duke University to Live in New Hampshire
1983 Passes Away
Collection Overview
Material includes lecture notes, papers concerning the Southeastern Personnel Conference, and papers related to Joerg's administrative duties at Duke.
Subject Headings
Duke University -- Administration; Duke University. Dept. of Economics -- Faculty
Detailed Description of Collection
- Container List, circa 1942-1967, 3.0 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1952 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Southeastern Personnel Conference (SPC) attendance, 1942 (Box 1)
  - SPC, 1953-1957 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, SPC, 1957-1962 (Box 1)
  - SPC, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Conference photos, circa 1947-1954 (Box 1)
  - SPC, miscellaneous brochures, memos (Box 1)
  - Dept. and Univ. correspondence, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, memos, incl. Undergraduate Faculty Council (Box 1)
  - UFC information, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Instruction, correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Men's SGA report, 1962 (Box 1)
  - ID and Training of Potential Scholars (Box 1)
  - Business/Econ dept., planning, memoranda, 1959-1960 (Box 1)
  - General tax info, 1955-1958 (Box 1)
  - Econ reading notes, 1947-1967 (Box 2)
  - Quiz, Exam, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Class notes on business development company (Box 2)
  - Corporation Finance class notes, 1949, undated (Box 2)
  - Econ 181 Exams, quizzes (Box 2)
  - Reading notes, undated (Box 2)
  - Harvard Business School, Business econ notes, exercises, 1958-1959 (Box 2)
  - Class notes, investments, undated (Box 2)
  - Corporation Finance, reading and class notes (Box 2)
  - Queens College Administrative Policy class, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Econ 143 notes, undated (Box 2)
  - Business/Finance reading notes (Box 2)
  - Queens Evening College, administrative practices, class notes, memos, undated (Box 2)
  - Econ 143 class notes, exercises (Box 2)
  - Econ 144 class notes, exercises (Box 2)
  - Econ 144 notes, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Dept, Duke, minutes, policies (Box 2)
  - Financial management (Box 2)
  - Business Law notes, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, memos, re: economics major, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Econ 143 notes and documents, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Econ development notes, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Investments, notes and quizzes, undated (Box 2)
  - Macro econ notes (Box 2)
  - Econ 143 class exercises, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Dept. memos, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Micro econ notes (Box 2)
  - Investments notes (Box 2)
  - Micro econ class notes (Box 2)
  - Corporate finance, notes and quizzes (Box 2)
  - Corporate finance reading notes (Box 2)
  - Course materials from other programs/schools (Box 2)